My name is Oliver Queen.
내 이름은 올리버 퀸
After five years
on a hellish island,
지옥 같은 섬에서
5년을 보낸 후
I have come home
with only one goal--
집으로 돌아 왔다.
목적은 오직 하나
to save my city.
내가 사는 도시를 지키는 것
But to do so, I can't be
the killer I once was.
하지만 그러기 위해서
예전처럼 살인자가 될 순 없다
To honor my friend's memory,
I must be someone else.
죽은 친구를 기리기 위해서
나는 다른 사람이 되어야 한다
I must be something else.
다른 무엇이 되어야 한다
Previously on "Arrow"...
'애로우' 지난 이야기...
This is my daughter, Helena.
내 딸 헬레나입니다
When her father
killed her fiancé,
아버지가 약혼자를 죽인 후로
she changed into something
dark and twisted.
그 여자는 사악하고
잔혹하게 변했어요
My father doesn't deserve
a second chance--
내 아버지는 누릴 자격이 없어.
새로운 기회도
a second life.
새로운 인생도
This is about
learning to control your strength.
관건은 네 힘을
통제하는 거야
Ollie, it's over!
We got to get off this ship!
올리, 끝났어!
배에서 도망쳐야 해!
Hugo mannheim.
휴고 맨하임
Warrants out for racketeering,
extortion, murder--
영장 발부 혐의는
갈취, 공갈, 살인
the goombah trifecta.
이탈리아계
삼종 세트야
But he never travels alone,
so watch your back,
절대 혼자 다니지 않으니
본인도 조심하고
watch your partner's back.
파트너도
잘 살펴주도록
Let's go.
가지
Thanks for helping me
keep watch over my dad tonight.
오늘밤 아빠 주변 망보는 일
도와줘서 고마워
As long as Slade's out there,
neither of our families are safe.
슬레이드가 있는 한
우리 둘 가족은 안전치 못해
This is the SCPD!
Put your weapons on the ground!
경찰이다!
바닥에 무기 버려!
Move, move, move!
가, 가, 가!
Aaah!
윽!
Freeze!
정지!
난 괜찮아.
가, 어서!
Go. Go!
Frank Bertinelli...
프랭크 버티넬리
My daughter
sent you to kill me.
내 딸이
날 죽이라고 보냈나
♪ Arrow 2x17 ♪
Birds of Prey
Original Air Date on March 26, 2014
♪ Arrow 2x17 ♪
Birds of Prey
Original Air Date on March 26, 2014
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man
Hey.
이봐들
Dad, are you all
right? Are you hurt?
아빠, 괜찮아요?
안 다쳤어요?
Yeah, I'm fine,
sweetheart.
그래, 괜찮다, 얘야.
Listen, I know you don't
exactly believe
저, 네가
미란다 원칙 같은 거
in reading perps
their Mirandas,
별로 신경 안 쓰는 건
알지만
but you can't just toss a guy
out of a window.
그렇다고 사람을
창밖으로 던지면 안 되지
He shot you.
아빨 쐈어요
And I'm still
here, ain't I?
그래도 멀쩡하잖니?
Just next time, show
a little restraint.
다음엔 좀,
약간만 자제하렴
That was me
showing restraint.
그게 자제한 건데요
Detective.
We have another problem.
랜스 형사,
다른 문제가 있습니다
Yeah, I know.
With Frank Bertinelli in custody,
알고 있어.
프랭크 버티넬리가 구금됐으니
it's just a matter of time before
She-Ro is back in town.
여전사께서 돌아오시는 건
시간 문제겠지
Who is she?
그 여자가 누군데?
Helena Bertinelli.
Daughter of mafia boss Frank Bertinelli.
헬레나 버티넬리.
마피아 보스 프랭크 버티넬리의 딸이죠
Or as I like to call
her, Oliver's psycho ex-girlfriend
저라면 아버지를 향한
복수심에 불타는 정신병자 겸
hell-bent on revenge
against her father.
올리버의 전 여자친구라
부르겠어요
Ex-girlfriend?
전 여자친구?
That's what you took
from that sentence?
방금 얘기에서
주목하는 게 그거야?
Wait, why does
she want her father killed so badly?
잠깐, 왜 그렇게 아버지를
죽이려고 하는 건데요?
He had her fiancé
murdered.
아버지가 약혼자를
살해했거든
She wants payback.
Puts the many fights
보복하려는 거지. /
내가 아빠랑 무진장
I've had with
my father in perspective.
싸웠던 일들이
달리 보이네
I've been
keeping tabs
작년 내내
헬레나의 행적을
on Helena over
the past year.
주시하고 있었어요
Last known sighting
was a month ago,
마지막으로 목격된 것은
지난달이었죠
Palermo.
팔레르모에서요
She's been busy.
If by "busy,"
바빴네요. /
바빴다는 게
you mean torturing
and killing mafiosos
아버지의 소재를 알지 모를
마피아 단원들을
that might know
where her father is.
고문하고 죽인다는
뜻이라면요
Bertinelli's arrest
just hit the wires.
버티넬리의 체포 소식이
방금 전파를 탔어요
How long do you think we have
before Helena books a ticket back home?
헬레나가 고향에 돌아올 때까지
얼마나 시간이 있을까요?
Go ahead.
시작해
Slade, please--
슬레이드, 제발...
Aah!
아아!
Why aren't we moving yet?
왜 아직
안 움직이지?
We managed to repair the hull.
선체는 겨우
수리를 했지만
But the engine is too damaged.
엔진은 파손이
너무 심해요
So fix it.
I can't.
그럼 고쳐. /
못 고쳐요
I don't know how!
고칠 줄을 몰라요!
Then find
somebody who does.
그럼 할 줄 아는 놈을
찾아
Hi, my name's Laurel,
I'm an alcoholic.
안녕하세요. 저는 로럴이고
알콜 중독입니다
Hi, Laurel.
안녕하세요, 로럴
And this is actually
my second meeting today.
사실 이 자리에 온 건
오늘이 두 번째예요
It's just, uh...
저는...
It's just so hard,
because I don't know
저를 정말
힘들게 하는 건
what to do
with myself all day.
하루 종일 뭘 해야할지
모르겠다는 거예요
I'm a lawyer,
저는 변호사예요
well, I...
was...a lawyer.
그러니까...
전직... 변호사죠
I loved it.
그 일이 좋았어요
But I guess I loved
drinking more.
하지만 술이 더
좋았나 봐요
I know that I can make it down here
with all of you.
여러분들이 있는 여기서라면
잘 해낼 자신이 있어요
I just...I'm not
sure I can make it out there.
그런데... 바깥 세상에서도
해낼 수 있을지는 모르겠어요
Anyway.
아무튼
Thank you for
letting me share.
얘기 들어주셔서
고마워요
Thanks for coming.
와줘서 고마워요
Sorry about the way
things ended here.
그렇게 끝났던 건
유감이에요
No, don't be.
그러실 거 없어요
You did me
a favor, Adam.
저한테 도움을 준
셈이죠, 애덤
It was the only way I was going
to hit bottom,
그 일 아니었으면
바닥을 치지 못했겠죠
and...
이제는...
And I did.
바닥을 쳤고요
How about you do me
a favor now...
이번엔 저한테
도움을 주면 어때요
come back to work.
복직해요
You want me back?
다시 돌아오라고요?
I'm looking for someone
to try this case that just came in,
방금 들어온 사건이 있는데
맡을 사람이 필요해요
and honestly, yours was
the first name that came to mind.
솔직히, 로럴 이름이
가장 먼저 떠오르더군요
I'm still facing sanctions
from the bar.
저 아직 자격 정지예요
Oh, I got a buddy
on the disciplinary committee.
아, 징계 위원회에
친구가 하나 있죠
I squared things for you.
다 처리해 뒀어요
An SCPD raid last night
brought in Frank Bertinelli.
어젯밤 경찰 급습으로
프랭크 버티넬리가 잡혔어요
He came back to Starling
to collect on some old debts.
오래된 빚을 받으려고
스탈링에 돌아온 거죠
Now, the DA's office
is clear to prosecute him;
이제 지방검찰청은
기소할 준비가 됐어요
for you to prosecute him.
로럴이 기소하는 거죠
I appreciate the offer, Adam,
but why me?
제의는 고마운데요, 애덤.
왜 하필 저죠?
Well, there are Rico counts
that your time at CNRI
뭐, 리코법 관련 조항들이 있으니
CNRI 경력이 있는 로럴이야말로
make you ideally suited for.
가장 적합한 사람이죠
Laurel, it's a case.
If you want it, it's yours.
로럴, 소송이에요.
마음만 먹으면 로럴 거예요.
But only if you're ready.
단, 준비가 됐다면요
What's the special occasion?
무슨 바람이 불었대?
I got paid.
So, you know,
월급 받았어.
그러니까 혹시
if you don't think
it's nice enough,
선물이 별로
마음에 안 들면
you only have
yourself to blame
월급 인상
안 해준
for not giving me
that raise.
본인 탓이란 것만
알아 둬
Oh!
오!
Roy, I love it.
로이, 맘에 꼭 들어
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
고마워
Hey, give me--
give me a second,
저, 잠깐...
잠깐만 다녀올게
I forgot to put
an order in.
주문 올리는 걸
잊었네
Ok.
그래
Hey, what's going on?
저기, 무슨 일 있어요?
I got a line on Michael Statton,
Helena's fiancé.
마이클 스태튼의 정보가 들어왔어요.
헬레나 약혼자요
Felicity, he's been
dead for five years.
펠리시티, 그 남자
5년 전에 죽었어요
Which makes the fact that he rented
a car last night very impressive.
그래서 어젯밤 차를 대여했다는
사실이 매우 인상적인 거죠
That's Helena.
헬레나로군
The car's got GPS,
I hacked into it.
GPS 달린 차예요.
제가 해킹했어요
Yeah. She's heading
straight for Starling City.
네, 직행 중이네요.
스탈링 시를 향해서
You ready to get
back in the field?
현장에 복귀할
준비는 됐어?
I thought you'd never ask.
언제 물어보나 했네요
It's over, Helena.
끝났어, 헬레나
Get out of the car!
차에서 나와!
Gun!
총!
Aah! Don't hurt me!
으아! 해치지 마세요!
Stand down.
물러서
Stand...Down!
물러서!
Don't hurt me!
Speedy!
해치지 마세요! /
스피디!
Enough!
그만!
He's just
Helena's decoy.
헬레나의 미끼였어
Where is she?
그 여자는 어디 있지?
I don't know!
몰라요
Some chick just paid
me to take the car for a joy ride.
그냥 어떤 영계가 돈을 주면서
이 차로 드라이브나 하라고 했어요
I swear!
진짜예요!
Please don't kill me.
제발 죽이지 마세요
I'm getting married
next month.
저 다음 달에 결혼해요
Just drive.
운전이나 해
According to the SCPD,
the guy that gave Helena
경찰에 따르면, 헬레나를 태우고
도시로 온 남자는 22살이래요
a ride into town is a 22-year-old
Poly Sci major at SCU,
스탈링 시립대에서
정치학을 전공하고 있고
and a member
of Gamma Tau,
대학 사교 클럽
회원이네요
which totally
explains the whole
그걸 보니 전부
이해가 가네요
"I didn't know I was aiding
and abetting a known felon" thing.
"저는 유명한 흉악범을 방조하고
있는 줄 전혀 몰랐어요" 하는 거
Anyone with boobs can get
a frat boy to do anything.
가슴만 달렸으면 사교 클럽 애들이야
마음대로 부려 먹을 수 있죠
I was a frat boy.
I rest my case.
나도 사교 클럽이었는데요. /
이상, 증명 끝
At least she didn't kill
him. That's something.
그래도 죽이진 않았잖아요.
많이 발전했네요
It's not like Helena
to show restraint.
자제력을 보이다니
헬레나답지 않아요
It sounds like
you have a type.
그게 이상형인가 봐
Keep tabs on the police.
경찰을 계속 주시해요
Let me know if they get
any leads on her.
경찰이 헬레나의 단서를
잡으면 알려줘요
I'll do some canvassing.
Hey...
난 발품 좀 팔아 보죠. /
저기
You ok?
Yeah.
괜찮아? /
네
By this time tomorrow,
it'll be like nothing happened.
내일 이 시간쯤이면
아무 흔적도 없겠죠
That's one upside
to Mirakuru.
미라쿠루의
장점 중 하나죠
The only one.
유일한 장점이지
Look, I know what
you're going to say.
무슨 말 하려는지
알아요
I had it under control
last night.
어젯밤엔 충분히
통제하고 있었어요
Yeah, so under control that I
almost put another arrow in you.
그래, 너무 통제를 잘해서
화살 한 대 더 꽂아 줄 뻔했지
I was going to back off,
but you never gave me a chance.
알아서 물러날 거였어요.
그럴 틈을 안 준 거죠
The only thing that
snapped you out of it
네가 흥분했을 때
정신 차리게 하는 건
was when
I brought up Thea.
테아 얘기뿐이더군
That's why
you called me Speedy.
그래서 날 스피디라
부른 거군요
I--I thought you were
trying to give me a nickname.
난... 난 무슨 별명이라도
붙여주는 건가 했네요
But for the record,
don't call me Speedy.
공식적으로 말하는데,
스피디라고 부르지 말아요
Noted.
그러지
Roy, you're dangerous.
로이, 너 위험해
I thought I was
helping you control it.
네가 힘을 통제하도록
도울 수 있을 줄 알았는데
You are. I mean, I can't look at
a bowl of water without slapping it.
도움 됐죠. 이젠 물그릇만 보면
꼭 때리게 되더라고요
The first time that you're out in
the field in weeks,
몇 주만에 처음으로
현장에 돌아왔는데
and...you're ready
to kill somebody?
벌써 누굴
죽일 작정이야?
Come on.
생각해 봐
I'm sorry, I should have asked
you to do this months ago.
미안하지만 부탁이 있어.
몇 달 전에 했어야 하는 건데
Asked me to do what?
무슨 부탁인데요?
Stay
away from Thea.
테아한테서 떠나줘
No, I--I can't.
안 돼요. 못해요
She's not safe when
she's around you.
네가 있으면
테아가 위험해져
I'm not sure anybody is
네가 분노에 빠져서
when you lose
yourself to this rage.
자신을 잃을 때는
누구도 안전하지 못해
You love her.
테아를 사랑하지
And that's why you're going to do
what I'm asking.
그렇다면 내 부탁을
들어야 해
Such a big uh-oh.
이게 무슨 일이래
Helena?
헬레나예요?
Laurel.
로럴이요.
Ada Adam Donner
애덤 도너 지방 검사보는
announced the return
of Laurel Lance to the DA's office
짧은 안식 기간을 마친
로럴 랜스 씨가
after a brief sabbatical.
지방검찰청에 복직한다고
발표했습니다
She will lead the prosecution
of Mr. Bertinelli.
속보
로럴 랜스 씨는 버티넬리 씨의
기소를 맡을 예정입니다
Jury selection starts today.
배심원단 선정은
오늘 시작됩니다
Hey.
안녕
Hey. What are
you doing here?
안녕. 무슨 일로 온 거야?
I heard you picked up
some big new case on the news.
뉴스를 보니
큰 건 맡았다면서
How come you didn't call me?
어떻게 전화도 안 해?
I was going to, but it
all happened so fast.
하려고 했는데 일이 너무
갑작스럽게 일어나서
Plus, I thought you and dad
would try and talk me out of
게다가 너랑 아빠는
너무 빨리 복직하는 걸
going back
to work so soon.
반대할 것 같았거든
Which is why
you're here.
그래서 온 거구나
I'm just worried about you.
그냥 언니가
걱정돼서 그래
If you're worried
I'm going to slip,
내가 또 엇나갈까 봐
그러나 본데
I'm still going to two meetings
a day, and--
나 지금도 하루에 두 번
모임에 나가고...
Laurel, it's not that.
언니, 그게 아냐
Everybody knows
what kind of guy Bertinelli is.
버티넬리가 어떤 사람인지는
세상이 다 알아
And not to mention
his completely psychotic daughter,
딸이라는 완전히
정신 나간 여자는 또 어떻고
who's already on her way back
to Starling City to kill him.
자기 아빠 죽이겠다고
스탈링 시에 돌아오고 있잖아
How do you know that?
네가 그걸 어떻게 아니?
I don't.
모르지
I just want you
to be safe.
그냥 언니가
위험한 게 싫어
And I love you
for caring.
신경 써 주는 건
정말 고마워
But Sara, you've never seen me be
a lawyer before.
근데 세라, 너 나 변호사
하는 거 본 적 없잖니
And I am really
good at it.
나 정말 잘한단 말야
And I miss it.
다시 일하고 싶었고
I have to run.
서둘러야겠다
I can't be late
for court.
법원에 늦으면
안 되지
Yeah, this is much better
than the freighter.
그래, 화물선보다
참 낫기도 하네
You prefer boat, Hendrik,
feel free to swim back.
배가 더 좋으면 헤엄쳐서
돌아가도 돼, 헨드릭
Sara said Oliver
survived here for over a year.
세라 말로는 올리버가
여기서 1년을 버텼대
We can do the same.
우리도 버틸 수 있어
Unless Ivo and his men
come find us.
아이보와 부하들이
우릴 찾으러 오지 않을 때 얘기지
We don't know
what happened on the boat.
배에서 무슨 일이
일어났는지 모르잖아
Who's alive
and who's dead.
누가 살았는지
누가 죽었는지
Sara, are you there?
세라, 거기 있나?
Slade! Is Oliver...
슬레이드! 올리버는...
He's in pain, yes.
고통 받고 있냐고? 맞아
But he's still
breathing--for now.
그래도 아직 숨은 붙어 있지...
당장은
Slade, listen, you won, ok?
You have the "Amazo."
슬레이드, 당신이 이겼어요. 됐죠?
어메이조는 당신 거예요.
Just let Oliver go,
and then you can leave us here!
그냥 올리버만 보내줘요.
그리고 우리는 두고 떠나요!
Well, here's
my problem, Sara.
그게 문젠데, 세라
I can't leave.
떠날 수가 없어
Why not?
During our assault,
왜죠? /
습격 도중에
the ship's engine
was damaged.
배의 엔진이
파손됐어
She won't sail.
항해를 못해
During the attack,
unfortunately
불행하게도
공격하던 중에
I decapitated
the engineer.
내가 기술자 목을
잘라 버렸거든
So what can we do
about our problem, Sara?
자, 우리 문제들을
어떡하면 좋을까, 세라?
You want Oliver back,
넌 올리버를 돌려 받고 싶고
and I need someone qualified
to fix this boat.
난 배를 수리할
기술자가 필요한데
For Oliver's sake,
I sure hope
올리버를
위해서라도
a Mr. Hendrik
is there with you.
거기 헨드릭 씨가
같이 있으면 좋겠군
Non-lethal arrows?
비살상 화살?
It's not like you
to play with kid gloves.
아동용 장갑 끼고
노는 건 안 어울려요
How's Roy?
로이는 어때요?
Like Helena, he is
not too pleased
헬레나처럼 로이도
내 선배 노릇이
with my skills
as a mentor.
썩 맘에 들지는
않나 봐요
Laurel won't drop the case.
She's headed to court right now.
언니가 소송 포기 안 한대.
지금 법원으로 향했어
Where are you going?
To the courthouse.
어디 가는 거야? /
법원에
Well, hey,
you forgot
잠깐, 여기
유아용 화살은
your baby arrows.
안 챙겨?
Look, I get your whole no
killing spree,
저기, 학살은 더 이상
않겠다는 건 알겠어
but if it comes down
to saving Laurel or killing Helena--
하지만 로럴을 구할지
헬레나를 죽일지가 걸렸다면...
Sara, those aren't
the only two choices.
세라, 선택이
그 둘만 있는 건 아냐
Well, you were happy enough
to let Dig take the kill shot
글쎄, 슬레이드가
자기 가족을 위협할 때는
when it was Slade
threatening your family.
딕이 저격하는 것도
별로 안 꺼리는 거 같던데
This is different.
이건 달라
I failed Helena.
헬레나를 망친 건 나야
I created the Huntress.
헌트리스를
만든 건 나라고
Yeah, well,
you created Slade, too.
그래, 근데, 슬레이드를
만든 것도 올리버잖아
You're right.
맞아
맞는 말이야
But when it comes
to our families...
하지만 가족이
얽혀 있을 때는
Neither one of us
thinks clearly.
너나 나나 제대로
생각을 못해
Which is why you have
to stay here.
그래서 너는
여기 있어야 하는 거야
Ollie.
올리
I can't.
그럴 수 없어
I'm not going to let
anything happen to Laurel.
로럴에게는 아무 일도
없도록 할게
I love her, too.
로럴은 나한테도 소중해
What do you guys think?
두 사람 생각은 어때요?
Oh, I think if the Huntress shows up,
you should totally kick her ass.
오, 전 헌트리스가 나타나면
세라가 혼쭐을 내줘야 한다고 봐요
Please don't tell me
you're worried about me, too.
너도 나 걱정된다는 말은
제발 말아줬으면 해
No, I just wanted
to watch the trial.
아니, 그냥 재판을
보고 싶어서
I heard the prosecutor
was something special.
검사가 좀 특별한
사람이라고 들었거든
That's odd.
Why are they bringing him in
이상하네.
왜 피고인을
through the front
entrance?
정문으로 데려오지?
Everybody get down!
모두 숙여요!
Hi, dad.
안녕, 아빠
Sorry I'm late, but you're a hard
man to track down.
늦어서 미안.
아빠 찾기가 좀 힘들더라구
But it's fitting
that you came back to Starling.
그래도 스탈링에 돌아온 건
적절했어
Where it all began.
여기서 모든 게
시작됐으니까
Where you killed
Michael.
여기서 아빠가
마이클을 죽였지
You know, I almost
feel sorry for you.
있잖니, 네가
안쓰러울 지경이구나
Helena...
헬레나...
Stop this.
이러지 마
Oliver,
you know I can't.
올리버, 이럴 수밖에
없는 거 알잖아
Well, what are you
waiting for?
뭘 기다리고 있어?
I said, what are you
waiting for?!
뭘 기다리고 있냐고
하잖아?
Helena Bertinelli,
put down your weapons
헬레나 버티넬리,
무기를 버리고
and place your hands
above your head.
머리 위로
손을 올려
So this was
a big trap...
그러니까 이게 다
함정이었다...
with you as the bait.
아빠가 미끼고
What did they offer you?
무슨 조건이었어?
Ah, they didn't have
to offer me anything.
아, 조건 같은 건
필요 없었지
Give up, Miss Bertinelli,
the building's surrounded.
포기해, 버티넬리 씨.
건물은 포위됐어
What was it you always
taught me, Daddy?
나한테 항상 가르쳤던 게
뭐였지, 아빠?
Be prepared
for anything.
모든 일에 대비하라
Fall back, fall back!
후퇴, 후퇴!
Take hostages,
and fall back.
인질 잡고 후퇴해
Hey, hold your fire, hold your fire!
They have hostages!
잠깐, 사격 중지, 사격 중지!
인질이 있어요!
Hold fire. Say it again, hold fire.
They've taken hostages.
사격 중지. 반복한다, 사격 중지.
인질을 잡고 있다
Where's Laurel? Where's Laurel?
Is she with you?
로럴은? 로럴은 어디 있어?
같이 있나?
I'm sorry, Mr. Lance,
we got separated.
죄송합니다, 랜스 씨.
중간에 떨어졌어요
She's still inside.
아직 안에 있어요
We are live outside
저희가 생중계 중인 곳은
the Starling City courthouse,
where Helena Bertinelli
스탈링 시 법원 밖입니다.
헬레나 버티넬리와
and an unknown number
of assailants
인원 불명의
괴한들이
seized control
of the entire building.
건물 전체를
장악하고 있습니다
And I'm not being told,
방금 들어온 소식에 따르면
they are holding a number
of hostages inside.
범인들은 건물 안에 상당수의
인질을 잡고 있다고 합니다
I want snipers
with thermals on top
두 블록 반경에 있는
모든 건물 옥상에
of every building
for a two block radius.
열 화상 조준경 장착한
저격수를 배치해
This was not how it was supposed
to go down, Captain!
이렇게 되면 안 되는 거
아니오, 대장
You promised me
there wouldn't be any casualties!
사상자는 없을 거라면서요!
This was your idea, huh?
You son of a bitch!
당신 생각이었단 말이지?
이 개자식아!
Hey, my daughter's
in there!
내 딸이
안에 있어!
What were
you guys thinking,
대체 무슨 생각으로
putting all those
innocent lives at risk?
무고한 인명을
위험에 빠뜨려?
Listen! I was following orders.
Orders?!
진정해요! 명령에 따랐을 뿐이오. /
명령?
Ms. Bertinelli.
버티넬리 씨
No one has
to die today.
아무도 죽을 필요는
없어요
My father does.
우리 아빤 죽어야 해
And unless
you hand him over to me,
우리 아빠를
데려오지 않으면
I'm going to start
killing hostages.
인질을 죽이기
시작하겠어
See this,
Mr. Donner,
보세요, 도너 씨
is what happens when you let
freaks with masks
가면 쓴 미친놈들이
멋대로 날뛰게 놔두면
run wild.
이런 일이 벌어지는 겁니다
Get them the hell
out of here.
저 사람들 끌어 내
건드리지 마
It's my mom.
어머니 전화네요
Detective.
랜스 형사
Helena Bertinelli
just took ten hostages.
헬레나 버티넬리가
방금 인질 열 명을 잡았어
Laurel's one of them.
로럴도 인질이야
Yeah, I'm aware
of the situation.
상황은 알고 있습니다
Oliver, where are you?
Are you ok?
올리버, 어디예요?
괜찮아요?
I'm with Lance as Oliver,
and he just called the Arrow.
올리버 신분으로 랜스 형사랑 같이 있어요.
형사가 방금 애로우한테 전화했어요
Oh. Oh!
오.
오!
It's getting really hard to keep track of
who knows whose secret identity.
누구 정체를 누가 아는지
점점 복잡해지네요
Felicity, Laurel is still
inside the courthouse.
펠리시티, 로럴은 아직
법원 안에 있어요
What do you
need, Oliver?
필요한 게 뭐죠, 올리버?
My work clothes.
I'm on it.
내 작업복이요. /
알았어요
Put Sara on the phone.
세라 바꿔 줘요
Uh...
어...
She's not here.
없는데요
Where is she?
어디 있죠?
Are you one
of the good guys?
당신은 좋은 편이에요?
No, but I'm friends with them.
아뇨, 다만 친구들이
좋은 편이죠
Dude, watch it.
Screw you!
이봐요, 조심해요. /
엿이나 먹어
Thea, we need to break up.
테아, 우리 헤어져야겠어
What?!
뭐?
No.
싫어
What do you mean, no?
무슨 말이야, 싫다니
Thea, I'm breaking up with you.
테아, 너랑 헤어진다고
No, you're not.
아니, 안 헤어져
You can't make me date you.
억지로 데이트라도 시키게?
Roy, yesterday
you gave me a bracelet
로이, 어젠 가진 돈
탈탈 털어서
worth every dime
that you had,
팔찌를 사주더니
and now what,
you want to end things?
지금은, 뭐,
나보고 끝내자고?
Look, you're clearly going through
something right now,
저기, 너한테 지금
무슨 일이 있는 거 알아
and I'm not going
to let you go through it alone.
그걸 너 혼자 겪게
하지는 않을 거야
I'm always going
to be here for you.
내가 항상 곁에
있을 거야
Sorry, Thea. The guy
from the private party
테아, 미안한데요,
별실 파티쪽 사람이
said we stocked the wrong vodka,
and he's freaking me out.
보드카 종류가 틀리대요.
아주 사람 환장하게 해요
Look, we'll talk
about this later, ok?
나중에 다시 얘기하자.
알았지?
Oh!
오!
Are you hurt?
다쳤어요?
I'm so stupid.
나도 참 멍청하죠
Hey.
잠깐
You don't want
to do that.
안 마시는 게
좋아요
Oh, no, trust me.
아뇨, 정말로
I do.
마시는 게
좋아요
What about
your sobriety?
금주는 어쩌고요?
How do you know about that?
그걸 어떻게 알죠?
The "A" chip on
your keychain.
열쇠고리에 달린
금주 모임 칩이요
30 days.
30일이군요
Do you even know
why I'm here today?
왜 내가 오늘 여기
있는지나 알아요?
Turns out I'm decoration.
알고 보니 나는
장식이더군요
Expendable decoration.
버려도 되는 장식
What do you mean?
무슨 말이죠?
This whole trial was a sham.
재판 전체가
가짜였어요
I should have seen it.
눈치챘어야 했는데
Sara was right.
세라 말이
맞았어요
Sara, she's...
세라는...
She's my sister.
내 여동생이에요
She said that I wasn't
ready to come back, and...
세라는 내가 아직 돌아올
준비가 안 됐다고 했죠
I just thought
she was being overprotective.
난 그냥 과보호라고만
생각했어요
Well, sisters
can be like that.
뭐, 자매란 게 그렇죠
You should
meet mine.
우리 언니를
만나봤어야 하는데
She's gone through a lot.
그 애는 힘든 일을
많이 겪었어요
She must have been so strong.
정말 강하게
견뎠을 거예요
I just...
난 그냥...
I wanted to show her,
show myself...
난 보여주고 싶었어요.
동생에게, 나 자신에게...
That I was still strong, too.
나도 여전히
강인하다는걸요
So show me.
그럼 나에게
보여줘요
Let's go.
가요
Where are you?
어디야?
Inside. I've got
Laurel Lance, she's ok.
건물 안. 로럴 랜스와
함께 있어. 무사해
Is that the Arrow?
애로우예요?
I'm headed to an egress point
in the south wing.
남쪽 동의 출구로
향하고 있어
Wait.
잠깐
What about
the other hostages?
다른 인질은
어쩌고요?
You're just going
to leave them?
그냥 놔두고
갈 거예요?
Look, I need
to get you to safety.
일단 당신을 안전한 곳으로
옮겨야겠어요
I don't understand! What
is so special about me?
이해가 안 돼요.
왜 나만 그렇게 특별하죠?
What's going on?
무슨 일이야?
She won't leave.
I know Helena.
로럴이 안 떠나겠대. /
난 헬레나를 알아요
She's going to kill
all of those people,
헬레나는 그 사람들을
다 죽일 거예요
innocent people.
무고한 사람들을
You wanted me to
show you I'm strong.
내가 강하다는 걸
보여달랬죠
This is me being
strong. I'm staying.
내 방식대로 보여주죠.
난 남겠어요
Are you going
to help me or not?
도와 줄 거예요,
말 거예요?
Get her out of there now!
어서 데리고 나와!
It's not like I can
just knock her out.
기절이라도
시키란 말이야?
I don't want you
engaging Helena.
헬레나랑은 절대
맞붙어선 안 돼
What, you're afraid
of what she'll do...
왜, 그 여자가 나한테
무슨 짓이라도 할까 봐?
Or what I'll do?
아님 내가 무슨 짓을
할까 봐?
Sara...You're not a killer.
세라... 넌 살인자가 아니야
I am what I need to be.
난 필요하면
뭐든 될 수 있어
Sara, did you hear me?
세라, 내 말 들었나?
I heard you.
들었어요
Hendrik's not here.
헨드릭은 여기 없어요
There's someone
I'd like you to say hello to.
인사시켜 줄
사람이 있어
Don't give him
anything, Sara.
그놈 말 듣지 마, 세라
Ollie!
올리!
One last chance.
마지막 기회야
Oliver for Hendrik.
헨드릭과 올리버를
교환한다
I told you! Look,
Hendrik, he didn't make it
말했잖아요! 헨드릭은
섬까지 못 왔어요
to the island, he drowned.
익사했어요
To think it was only a year ago,
you were a little college girl,
그러고 보니 1년 전만 해도 넌
남자 문제로 속이나 태우는
fretting about boys.
어린 여대생이었지
What's your point?
하고 싶은 말이
뭐죠?
You're not a good liar.
거짓말이
서툴러
Slade!
Stop, please!
슬레이드!
그만해요, 제발!
Look, he's
your friend!
올리버는 친구잖아요!
That is the sound of electricity
surging through my friend.
방금은 내 친구 몸에
전류가 흐르는 소리였어
Five milliamps,
to be exact.
5 밀리암페어지,
정확히는
Seven causes
cardiac arrest.
7 밀리암페어면
심장 마비가 와
Aah!
아악!
Oliver just passed out with
six milliamps.
올리버가 방금 기절했어.
6 밀리암페어였지
He'll be delivered with
the fatal blow of seven
1시간 후엔 치명적인
7 밀리암페어를 흘릴 거야
in one hour if Hendrik
싫으면 그때까지
is not standing here
by my side!
헨드릭을 내 앞에
데려와!
There's no way
in hell I'm going back there.
난 죽어도
저기 안 돌아가
I was almost married once.
나도 한때는 거의
결혼할 뻔했었지
It's been an hour,
1시간 지났어
and I'm a woman
of my word.
난 약속은
지키는 여자지
Just ask my father.
우리 아빠한테 물어 봐
No, please!
Everything's going to be ok.
다 괜찮을 거예요
Behind you!
뒤요!
Oliver sure does like
to dress up his girls.
올리버는 정말 자기 여자
옷 입히는 걸 좋아하네
You all right?
괜찮아?
Laurel! She's
still in there.
언니! 아직
안에 있어
Nice to see you
again, Laurel.
또 보니 반갑네, 로럴
Helena,
listen to me.
헬레나, 내 말 들어
This has to end.
I agree.
이젠 끝내야 해. /
맞아
And it ends with
my father in a box.
우리 아빠가 관 속에
들어가면 끝이 나지
The police are never
going to hand over your father!
경찰이 당신 아버지를
넘겨 줄 것 같아?
No, they won't.
안 그러겠지
That's why you're
going to do it.
그러니까 당신이 해
Simple trade--
간단한 교환이지
my father for Laurel.
우리 아빠와 로럴
Hey, guys?
여기요?
We need more vodka.
보드카가 더
있어야겠어요
Ok...
좋아요
I'll get it myself.
내가 직접 가져 오죠
Where are you taking me?
어디로 데려가는 거요?
Safe house.
안전 가옥
Listen, front's mobbed
with reporters.
잠깐, 정문엔
기자들이 깔렸어
Let's take Bertinelli
out the back.
뒷문으로 데려 가자고
Bring the van
around.
밴을 뒤로
돌려
Ow! All right.
아야! 알았다고
Whoa! What the hell?
Don't worry about it.
워, 무슨 짓이야?
걱정 마
What's going on?
Just get in the van!
무슨 일이야?
밴에 타기나 해!
Hey!
이봐!
Hey, hey!
이봐, 이봐!
SWAT's getting ready to
breach the courthouse.
경찰특공대가
돌입 준비 중이야
Then we make
the trade now.
그럼 당장
교환해야겠네
Listen, I'm not going
to lose any sleep over Frank.
나야 프랭크가 죽는다고
잠 못 이루지야 않겠지만
But are you really going
to serve him up to his daughter?
정말 프랭크를 딸에게
갖다 바칠 셈인가?
No.
아뇨
No one dies tonight.
오늘밤 죽는 사람은
없을 겁니다
Are you ok?
괜찮아요?
Everything's
going to be fine.
다 잘될 거예요
I said...no talking.
입 다물라고 했지
We talked that night.
우리 그 날 밤
대화한 적 있죠
You, Oliver,
Tommy, and I.
당신, 올리버, 토미, 나
At dinner.
저녁 식사였죠
I remember you telling me
your fiancé was killed.
약혼자가 살해당했다고
했던 게 기억나요
I'm so sorry.
정말 안됐어요
Does this make us
girlfriends?
그러니까 우리 이제
친구 하자고?
No.
아뇨
But I know what
it's like to lose someone.
하지만 누굴 잃어버린
심정이 어떤지는 알아요
Ohh.
어우
Poor Laurel.
불쌍한 로럴
Did Tommy dump you?
토미한테 차이셨나?
No.
아뇨
He died.
토미는 죽었어요
And I couldn't deal with it.
난 그걸 받아들일 수가
없었죠
So I became a drunk.
그래서 알콜 중독이 됐어요
Every problem I had,
문제가 생길 때마다
I solved with a pill or a drink.
약이나 술로 해결했죠
My friends and my family,
친구들, 가족들
they tried to help me,
but I wouldn't let them.
모두 도와주려 했지만
내가 받아들이지 않았어요
You don't have
to do this, Helena.
이럴 필요 없어요, 헬레나
It's not too late.
아직 늦지 않았어요
Yes, I do.
아니, 늦었어
Because once you let
the darkness inside,
한번 어둠을
받아들이고 나면
it never comes out.
다시 돌이킬 수 없거든
Helena.
I have your father.
헬레나. 당신 아버지를
데리고 있어
Hmm.
I want four men teams,
diamond formations.
4명씩 팀을 짠다.
다이아몬드 대형이다
Move fast, shoot sharp.
신속하게 이동하고
정확하게 사격해라
One more thing--
vigilantes are not the law.
한 가지 더.
자경꾼들은 법이 아니다
If they're wearing a mask,
they get a bullet.
가면 쓴 놈을 보면
총알을 먹여줘라
Let's move out.
움직이자
Hands up, Bertinelli!
Do it now!
손 들어, 버티넬리!
당장!
Please don't
kill me! Please!
죽이지 마세요!
제발!
She--she told me--
그, 그 여자가
she told me to wear it
or she'd kill me!
그 여자가 이거 안 입으면
죽인댔어요!
Where the hell is she?!
젠장 어디 간 거야!
Don't look so scared, Laurel.
You might just live through this.
너무 겁먹은 표정 하지 마, 로럴.
혹시 살아 남을지도 모르잖아
So you're just going
to hand me over to my daughter?
그러니까 나를 그냥
내 딸한테 넘기겠다?
I thought you were
the good guys!
당신들은 좋은 편인 줄
알았는데!
Shut up.
입 다물어
Remember all that
stuff I said about restraint?
내가 자제가 어쩌고
했던 거 기억해?
Forget about it.
잊어버려
Hey.
이봐
You can't stop someone like Helena
by becoming her.
헬레나와 똑같은 사람이 된다고
헬레나를 막을 수는 없어
I'll do what I have to
to protect someone I love.
소중한 사람을 지킬 수 있다면
난 뭐든 할 거야
Hendrik, please,
put the gun down!
헨드릭, 제발
총 내려 놔!
Why? So you can send me
왜? 그 지옥에
back to that hell hole?
I don't think so!
날 돌려보내게?
그렇겐 안 되지!
It's not for any
of us to decide
누가 살고
누가 죽을지는
who lives and dies.
우리가 선택할
일이 아니야
But in Hendrik's case,
I'd be willing to make an exception.
하지만 헨드릭의 경우엔
예외로 해도 좋을 거 같은데
I'm leaving.
Don't stop me.
난 갈 거야.
막을 생각 마
Good at talking,
but you will not kill me.
말은 잘하지만,
날 죽이진 못할걸
Let's find out.
확인해 보자구
Sir, we've got a ping off
Ms. Lance's cell phone.
랜스 씨의 휴대전화
신호를 확인했습니다
She must still
have it on her.
아직 전화를
지니고 있습니다
Where?
어디지?
A machine shop
at Gail Street and Simone.
게일 가와 시몬 로에 있는
공장입니다
Should we rally up there?
거기 집결할까요?
Negative.
Hold your location.
아니다.
현재 위치를 고수하라
Yes, sir.
알겠습니다
Sergeant,
keep this position.
경사, 이 위치
유지해
Yes, sir.
Well, this is irony
for you, dad.
이거 아빠한테는
아이러니네
Didn't you have
Jimmy d'Agostino's body
아빠가 지미 다고스티노의
시체를 묻은 게
buried under
the building next door?
옆 건물 아래
아니었나?
I'm sorry, my girl.
미안하구나, 얘야
Now you're about to die,
I'm sure you are.
이제 죽게 생겼으니
당연히 그럴 테지
No.
아니
I'm sorry for that little girl
I used to take to ballet class.
그 어린 여자아이한테 미안해.
발레 교습에 데려다 주곤 했던 아이
Go on ski trips with.
같이 스키 여행 갔던 아이
The one I used to help
with her math homework.
내가 수학 숙제를
도와주곤 했던 아이
Oh, she hated math.
오, 수학을 정말
싫어했지
Sorry that I caused her
so much hurt.
그 애를 그토록 아프게 해서
미안하다
'Cause she brought me
so much joy.
그 앤 나한테 너무나
큰 기쁨을 주었거든
Helena!
헬레나!
Don't kill him.
죽이면 안 돼
You can never
come back from that.
죽이면 다시는
돌아올 수 없어
It's too late.
너무 늦었어
I'm already gone.
난 이미
못 돌아와
Bye, Dad.
잘 가, 아빠
Damn vigilantes!
망할 자경꾼들!
You went above the law!
네놈들이 법보다
높은 줄 아나!
Last time this happened,
I threw you out a window.
지난번엔 내가 널
창밖에 내던졌었지
I was holding back.
그땐 좀 살살
했거든
I won't do that again.
이젠 아냐
Hey.
이봐
No!
안 돼요!
You're not a killer.
당신은 살인자가
아니에요
You don't know who I am,
Laurel, not really.
내가 어떤 사람인지
잘 모르잖아요, 로럴
Then show me.
그럼 보여줘요
No...
안 돼
It was supposed
to be me.
나였어야 해
It was supposed
to me who did it.
내가 했어야 한다구
All right, Bertinelli,
that's enough.
이제 됐어, 버티넬리.
그만 하지
Go.
가요
How did you
get in here?
어떻게 들어온 거야?
My family makes a generous donation
to the policemen's retirement fund.
우리 가족은 경찰 은퇴기금에
상당한 기부를 하고 있거든
And every once in a while,
I get to call in a favor.
그래서 이따금씩은 그쪽에서
내 부탁을 들어주는 거지
Hmm. Maybe you could
ask them to send me
흐음. 그럼 어딘가
열대 지방의 감옥에
to prison
somewhere tropical.
날 보내 달라고
부탁해도 되겠네
You know, I thought
I'd feel different
있잖아, 난 뭔가 기분이
달라질 줄 알았어
now that he's dead,
but I don't.
이젠 아빠가 죽었는데
그렇지가 않네
And you always
told me that...
나한테 항상 그랬었지
Killing him wouldn't
change anything.
아빠를 죽인다고
달라지는 건 없다고
You were right.
그 말이 맞았네
But I was wrong, too.
나도 틀린 게 있어
About what?
뭘?
I thought I could help you.
난 널 도울 수
있다고 생각했어
Stop you from being a killer,
살인을 멈추게
할 수 있다고
but...
하지만...
I was just starting.
그땐 나도
막 시작이었어
And I was a killer, too.
나 역시 살인자였고
And what
are you now?
그럼 지금은 뭔데?
I'm trying to be better.
더 나은 사람이
되려는 중이지
It's so stupid,
but...
참 바보 같은
소리지만...
I keep thinking,
now that he's dead,
자꾸 그런 생각이 들어.
이제 아빠가 죽었으니
my father and Michael
are together, and...
아빠하고 마이클은
함께 있을 거라고
I'm still here.
근데 난 여기 있고
Alone.
혼자
You're not alone.
넌 혼자가 아냐
What are you doing to me?
나한테 뭐하는 거야?
In Roman times,
로마 시대엔
a criminal was branded
죄인에게
낙인을 찍었다지
to identify his crimes
to the world
세상에 그 죄가
드러나고
and to forever remind
him of what he'd done.
자신이 저지른 일을
두고두고 되새기라고
Shado wore this
tattoo on her back.
샤도는 등에
이 문신이 있었지
Now you shall wear
it for the rest of your life,
이제 그 문신을 평생
지니고 살게 될 거야
however short
that may be.
그 평생이 얼마나
될진 몰라도
슬레이드
슬레이드!
Hello, Sara.
안녕, 세라
I hope you've made
the right choice.
올바른 선택을
내렸길 바라
Yes.
그랬어요
Look, on behalf of
the entire DA's office,
저, 지방검찰청
전체를 대신해
I have to apologize.
사과를 해야겠군요
Adam Donner's employment
here has been terminated.
애덤 도너는
파면됐어요
Obviously we had no idea
what he was plotting.
당연히 우리는 그 사람이
꾸미는 일을 전혀 몰랐죠
I would hope not.
그게 사실이길
바라요
Unfortunately, Adam
was not authorized
안타깝게도 애덤은
당신한테 복직을 제의할
to offer you
your job back.
권한이 없었어요
I'm sorry,
안됐지만
but nothing
has changed.
달라진 건 없어요
Yes, it has.
아뇨, 달라졌죠
Excuse me?
뭐라고요?
You are going
to rehire me, Kate.
절 다시
고용하셔야겠어요, 케이트
Unless you feel like
explaining to the press
오늘밤의 인질극을
야기한 전략의 귀재가
that your own assistant
district attorney
다름 아닌 검사님의
지방 검사보라고
was the brilliant mastermind
behind tonight's hostage crisis.
언론에 알리고 싶지
않으시다면 말이죠
Welcome back.
복직 환영해요
I have to say,
I am impressed.
사실 좀
감명 받았어요
I would have thought blackmail was
a little dark for you.
협박 같이 음험한 일은 당신한테
좀 안 어울린다고 생각했는데
Someone recently told me,
최근에 누가 그러더군요
once you let
the darkness inside,
한번 어둠을 받아들이면
it never comes out.
다시 돌이킬 수
없다고
Hey.
안녕
What are you still
doing up here?
이 시간에
여기서 뭐 해?
Thinking.
생각해
Crying.
울어
Roy and I are...
로이랑 나...
What happened?
어떻게 된 거야?
I caught him
with some slut.
로이가 어떤 년이랑
그러고 있는 걸 봤어
Right over
there, actually.
바로 저기였어,
사실은
I'm sorry.
안됐구나
He was doing it
to push me away,
날 밀어내려고
일부러 그런 건데
which clearly
worked.
확실히
효과 있네
I just...
I don't know why.
난 그냥...
이유를 모르겠어
Why is it so hard
for everyone
그냥 사실대로
말하는 게
just to tell
the truth?
왜들 그렇게 힘든 거야?
I mean, Roy can't even
tell me the truth
로이는 왜 나랑
끝내려는 건지도
of why he wants to
end things with me.
사실대로 말을 못해
Mom, she...
엄마는...
She keeps all
of these secrets.
엄마는 비밀이
너무 많아
I mean, doesn't it...
그러니까, 엄마가...
Doesn't it feel like she's still keeping
something from us?
엄마가 우리한테 아직
숨기는 게 있는 거 같지 않아?
I don't know, Thea.
모르겠어, 테아
You're the only one
that doesn't lie to me, Ollie.
나한테 거짓말 안 하는 건
올리 오빠밖에 없어
You're the only one
I know
내가 아는 사람 중에
who doesn't keep
secrets from me.
나한테 비밀이 없는 건
오빠뿐이야
Just, I got to go.
나 이만 가야겠다
Let me drive you.
태워줄게
No, I just want to be
alone right now.
아니, 지금은 그냥
혼자 있고 싶어
Is she ok?
괜찮아?
She will be.
괜찮아질 거야
Eventually.
언젠가는
You did good
tonight.
오늘밤 훌륭했어
That's what heroes do, right?
영웅은 그래야
하는 거잖아?
It's a dangerous city.
이 도시는 위험해요
You shouldn't be out
in the streets alone.
아가씨 혼자서 거리를
돌아다니면 안 되죠
Mr. Wilson?
윌슨 씨?
Please.
Call me Slade.
부디,
슬레이드라 부르세요
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
@elder_man